Theodore Roosevelt Jr. Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1919-1960 (Box 40-54)
  - Article File, 1919-1943 (Box 50-51)
    - By Theodore Roosevelt (1887-1944)
      - Handwritten drafts
        - Cosmopolitan Magazine articles on Kelley-Roosevelt-Field Museum expedition, 1928-1929
        - Untitled, re Sergeant Rose, undated
      - Texts
        - 1920-1932, (8 folders)
        - 1933-1941, (7 folders) (Box 51)
  - Book File, 1926-1960 (Box 51-54)
    - By Eleanor Butler Roosevelt, Day Before Yesterday (1959) (Box 51)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1960, (4 folders)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1959 (Box 52)
      - Legal papers, 1958
      - Permissions, 1948-1958
      - Photographs, undated
      - Publicity, 1959
      - Research material, 1958, undated
      - Reviews, 1959
      - Miscellany, 1959
      - Typescript draft (chiefly carbons), undated, (8 folders) (Box 53)
    - By Theodore Roosevelt (1887-1944) (Box 54)
      - East of the Sun and West of the Moon (1926)
        - Comments, 1926-1927
        - Publication rights, 1925-1926
      - Rank and File (1928)
        - Chapter topics and related individuals
          - Dunn, Parker, 1927
          - Ellis, Michael, 1927
          - Hays, George P., 1927
          - Johnson, Henry, 1927
          - Kishler, Edwin P., 1927
          - Kocak, Matej, 1927
          - Luke, Frank, 1927
          - Miles, Wardlaw, 1927-1928
          - Rodgers, John, 1927
          - Wiggins, Sgt., 1927
          - York, Alvin, 1926-1927
        - General comments, 1927-1940
        - Publishing correspondence, 1926-1927
      - Taps (1932), general comments, 1930-1933
      - Colonial Policies of the United States (1937)
        - Comments, 1937
        - Publication rights, 1937
      - The Desk Drawer Anthology (1937), correspondence and notes, 1937-1942
- Miscellany, 1780-1960 (Box 55-62)
  Holograph, typewritten, and printed material including guest lists, financial and household records, awards, certificates, and correspondence.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Army identification cards, 1941 (Box 55)
  - Autographs, 1846-1927
  - Awards, 1935-1943, undated
  - Baby journal, Archibald, Ethel, Kermit, Quentin, and Theodore Roosevelt, undated
  - Balance sheet of expenses incurred by Elizabeth Hart, Philadelphia, Pa., 1780
  - Biographical information
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor Butler, 1955-1959, undated
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (1887-1944), 1894-1899, 1924-1944, 1957
  - Bride book, Eleanor Butler Roosevelt, 1910
  - Citations and memorials, Theodore Roosevelt (1887-1944), 1907, 1918-1927, 1943-1948, 1955
  - Citations and memorials, Theodore Roosevelt (1858-1919) and Theodore Roosevelt (1887-1944), 1927-1936, 1943-1960, undated (Box 56)
  - Christmas card lists, undated (Box 57)
  - Dinner parties lists, 1910-1933
  - Fishing parties lists, 1932
  - Gift lists, 1920-1951
  - Financial material, 1887, 1927-1942 (Box 58)
  - Butler genealogy, 1919
  - Garden notebook, 1910
  - Harvard University Library, Cambridge, Mass., deposit of letters of Theodore Roosevelt, Sr., 1947-1958 (Box 59)
  - Household decoration book and recipes, 1937-1938
  - Household records, 1928-1949
  - Lecture dates and topics, Eleanor Butler Roosevelt, 1935-1947
  - Memberships, 1920-1941
  - Messages, Philippine Islands, 1932-1937
  - Miscellaneous letters, 1876, 1888
  - Note regarding Kermit Roosevelt, undated
  - Official certificates and oaths, 1874, 1932, undated
  - Official documents concerning the death and estate of Emily Tyler Carow, 1939 (Box 60)
  - Poetry, unidentified, undated
  - Scraps, miscellaneous notations, 1935, 1944, undated
  - Signature books of guests at various homes occupied by Theodore and Eleanor Butler Roosevelt, 1910-1960, (2 vols.)
  - Travel itinerary, Eleanor Butler Roosevelt, 1955-1958, undated
  - Typescripts
    - Clippings concerning Roosevelt's governor-generalship of the Philippines, 1932, undated
    - Correspondence
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor Butler, to her mother, 1917-1918, (2 folders)
      - Roosevelt, Theodore (1858-1919), to Theodore Roosevelt (1887-1944), 1896-1918, (2 folders) (Box 61)
      - Roosevelt, Theodore (1887-1944), to various family members, 1917-1919, 1941-1944, (5 folders)
      - Special correspondence and autographs, 1920-1944, (3 folders) (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous transcripts, 1920-1959
    - Narrative concerning attempted assassination of Theodore Roosevelt (1858-1919), 1912
- Printed Matter, 1894-1959 (Box 63-76)
  Newspaper clippings, photocopies of clippings, books, and monographs.
  Arranged by type of material and, in the case of the newspaper clippings, in chronological order by year.
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 63)
    - Originals
      - 1894-1933, (6 folders)
      - 1917-1937, encodinganalog="245$f" unitdatetype="inclusive">1917-1937; (14 folders) (Box 64)
      - 1920-1924, encodinganalog="245$f" unitdatetype="inclusive">>1920-1924; (5 folders) (Box 65)
      - 1924-1929, (4 folders) (Box 66)
      - 1927-1940, (4 folders) (Box 67)
      - 1932-1943, (10 folders) (Box 68-69)
      - 1944-1953, (10 folders) (Box 70)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 71)
    - Photostatic copies
      - 1894-1923, (10 folders)
      - 1924-1933, (15 folders) (Box 72)
      - 1932-1942, (18 folders) (Box 73)
      - 1943-1953, (18 folders) (Box 74)
  - Various publications, 1919-1944, 1956-1959, undated (Box 75-76)
- Papers of Theodore Roosevelt (1858-1919), 1876-1918 (Box 77)
  Letters to and from Theodore Roosevelt and one speech. Arranged by type of material.
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and chronologically therein.
  - Correspondence (Box 77)
    - Cutler, Arthur, 1876
    - Dockery, A. V., 1912-1916
    - Gilman, Bradley, 1912
    - Gray, Ellen, 1897
    - Hanna, Marcus Alonzo (Mark), 1902-1903
    - Perkins, Robert, 1918
    - Roosevelt, Edith Kermit Carow, 1898
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (1887-1944), re military service, 1918
  - Speech, "Put the Flag On the Firing Line!" 1917, undated